Guide to the Seneca Club of Kings County records 2016.042
Brooklyn Historical Society
Seneca Club of Kings County records
1928-2018
1961-1985
Center for Brooklyn History
Seneca Club of Kings County (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
2016.042
12.16 Linear Feet in ten manuscript boxes, nine shoe boxes, and three oversize flat boxes
The Seneca Club of Kings County was established in 1899 in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, and is the oldest Democratic club in Brooklyn. The Seneca Club provides a social setting for community leaders, elected representatives, and public officials to meet and discuss issues important to the community and neighborhood. The Club helps citizens with local problems, such as housing, job placement, and neighborhood conditions. This collection includes administrative and financial records, correspondence from local residents on personal and local issues, and ephemera from electoral campaigns and the Seneca Club's annual Dinner-Dance. This collection also includes photographs of Seneca Club events, members, affiliated organizations, and prominent politicians.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Steven D. Cohn, Gerald Esposito, Minerva Moises, Ramona Vergara, John Witkowski, and Marc Liebman, 2016.
Appraisal
Routine financial documentation and correspondence was removed from the collection, as were newspaper clippings and blank forms. Duplicate material, including a substantial quantity of duplicate sample ballots, were removed from the collection. Plaques were reviewed in consultation with the donor, and the majority were discarded.
Copies of New York Red Book: An Illustrated Legislative Manual of the State (from 1912, 1929, 1930 and 1943) were separated to the library collection.
Historical note
The Seneca Club of Kings County was established in 1899 with headquarters originally at 125 Division Ave and later at 93 Division Ave, in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn. The club was formed in the wake of 1898 vote to consolidate Manhattan, Brooklyn, Queens, Staten Island and the Bronx into New York City, which the Seneca Club founders opposed. The Seneca Club was led by prominent leaders such as Frank Kelly from 1944 to 1946, Joesph Sharkey from 1946 to 1962, Leonard Scholnick from 1962 to 1972, Abraham Gerges from 1972 to 1982, and Steven D. Cohn since 1982. It is the oldest Democratic club in Brooklyn.
The Seneca Club provides a social setting for community leaders, elected representatives, and public officials to meet and discuss issues important to the community and neighborhood. The Club helps citizens with local problems, including housing, job placement, and neighborhood conditions. The Seneca Club holds an annual dinner at Polonaise Terrace in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the internal organization of the the Seneca Club, through administrative and financial records, as well as the club's interactions with local residents. Correspondence from local residents addresses personal and local issues such as housing, immigration status, military service, and employment. Seneca Club's annual Dinner-Dance is documented through souvenir programs and other ephemera. Electoral campaigns are similarly represented through ephemera, a sample voting maching, and a ledger containing handwritten and published election results, clippings, and campaign advertisements. This collection also includes photographs of Seneca Club events, members, affiliated organizations, and prominent politicians.
Related Materials
Puerto Rican Oral History Project records (1976.001), Interview with Edna Rosado Oliveras
Alan Maisel and Bernard Catcher collection on Brooklyn politics (2016.001)
Brooklyn Democratic Club records (1978.145)
United Progressive Democratic Club records (2005.018)
Civitas Club collection (ARC.300)
Elections |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Ledgers (account books); Clubs -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Political clubs |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Low-income housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Neighborhood government |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Fundraising |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Ephemera; Correspondence; Cashbooks; Democratic Party (New York, N.Y.)
- Series 1: Administrative Records, 1945-2009
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains internal administrative and financial records for the Seneca Club of Kings County. Financial records include leases and a mortgage for the Club headquarters at 93 Division Ave, tax documents, cash books, and expense ledgers. Administrative records include membership ledgers, Executive Committee meeting minutes and correspondence, and certificates and proclamations. Also included are ledgers from the War Effort and Entertainment committees.
  Arrangement
  Material in this series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - 93 Divison Ave Lease, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 93 Divison Ave Mortgage, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advertisers War Effort Committee Ledger, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Applications Ledger for Housing at Jonathan Williams Plaza, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Bills Paid Ledger, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Books Distributed Ledger, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cash Book, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cash Book, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cash Book, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Certificates, 1972-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Disbursements Ledger, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Donations and Funding, 1970-2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Entertainment Committee Ledgers, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Executive Committee, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gavels, undated (Box 20)
  - Harold Cohn Certificates, 1960-1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Membership Applications, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Membership ID Cards, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Membership Dues, 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Membership Ledger, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Membership Ledgers, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Membership Ledger, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Membership Sign-In Sheets, 1984-1986 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Officers, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Proclamations, City of New York, 1999-2009 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Seneca Club Certificates, 1997-2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Seneca Club Raffle, 1964-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Seneca Club War Efforts Committee Members, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Steve Cohn Certificates, 1970-1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Tax Documents, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Tax Returns and Documents, 2003-2008 (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
- Series 2: Correspondence and Subject Files, 1951-2009
  The majority of material in this series is comprised of correspondence from local residents to elected officials and Seneca Club representatives regarding local and personal matters. Elected officials often referred constituent correspondence to the Seneca Club, and conversely the Seneca Club lobbied elected representatives on behalf of neighborhood residents. There is a significant body of correspondence regarding employment opportunities, immigration status, and military service, including deferements and reassignments of active duty soldiers during the Vietnam War. There is also a significant group of correspondence with the New York City Housing Authority (NYCHA) regarding the availability of apartments in new NYCHA developments. Other topics represented in constituent correspondence include crime and incarceration, federal benefits, education, and local development issues in Williamsburg and Greenpoint. The series also includes correspondence from Seneca Club leaders, and a small number of subject files.
  - Abe Gerges Personal Correspondence, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Allard Lowenstein Controversy, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Benefits, 1959-1972 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Clermont Ave Armory Community Center, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Council Of Jewish Organizations Of Flatbush, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Crime, 1966-1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Education, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Employment, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
  - Finance Department Drawings, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fort Greene Correspondence and Newsletter, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - George Swetnick Personal Correspondence, 1963-1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Greenpoint Food Depot, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Greenpoint Incinerator, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Housing, 1960-1980 (Box 3, Folder 18-21, Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Immigration, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Incarceration, 1964-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Invitations and Greetings, 1959-2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Sharkey Resignation, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - John Smolenski Memorial Democratic Club Inc., Banquet, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Reports, 1976-1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - MTA Campaign, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mid-Brooklyn Health Association, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Mid-Brooklyn Health Association, Neighborhood Health Center Blueprints, 1972 (Flat file folder 1)
  - Military Service, 1961-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
  - Miscellaneous Bulletins, 1974-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Constituent Correspondence, 1962-1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-2005 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - National Congress Of Neighborhood Women Newsletter, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Neighborhood Conditions, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - New York City Housing Authority Brochures, 1973-1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - NYC Municipal Government Bulletins, 1967-1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Nomination and Endorsement Correspondence, 1973-2004 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - North Brooklyn Development Corporation, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - North Brooklyn Independent and Friends Of McCarran Park Inc., 1984-2004 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Police Brutality, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Police Precinct Closure, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Preliminary Report of the Senate Democratic Force on NYC, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Program Funding, 1965-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Proxy Paperwork, 1970-1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pulaski Association of Business and Professional Men, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Redistricting Fact Sheet, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Resignations, 1953-1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Seneca Club Mailings, 1965-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - St. Stanislaus Memorial Post, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Steve Cohn Personal Correspondence, 2001-2009 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Survey of the NYC Mortgage Program, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Taxation, 1966-1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Zoning and Rehabilitation, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Series 3: Seneca Club Events, 1931-2018
  Souvenir programs and other ephemera from the Seneca Club's annual Dinner-Dance comprise the majority of this series, with the bulk of programs dating from the Diamond Jubilee dinner in 1973 until the present. A number of earlier Seneca Club events are also represented in this series, as well as several programs from the Brooklyn Democrats Awards Dinner.
  Material in this series is arranged chronologically.
  - Souvenir Program, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Seneca Night, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Event Brooklet, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Annual Dinner and Dance, 1962-1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Diamond Jubilee Dinner, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 76th Anniversary Annual Dinner-Dance, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Annual Dinner and Dance RSVPs, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 77th Anniversary Annual Dinner-Dance, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Annual Dinner and Dance RSVPs, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 79th Anniversary Annual Dinner-Dance, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Annual Dinner and Dance RSVPs, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Seneca Dinner Ledger, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 87th Annual Dinner-Dance, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Brooklyn Democrats Awards Dinner, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 98th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn Democrats Awards Dinner, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn Democrats Awards Dinner, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Democrats Awards Dinner, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - King County Democratic County Committee Awards Dinner, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 102nd Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 102nd Anniversary Annual Dinner and Dance RSVPs, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 103rd Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 104th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 105th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 105th Anniversary Annual Dinner and Dance RSVPs, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Dinner-Dance Proclamations, Borough of Brooklyn, 2004-2013 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 106th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 106th Anniversary Dinner and Dance RSVPs, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 107th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 108th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 108th Anniversary Dinner Dance RSVPs, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 109th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 109th Anniversary Dinner Dance RSVPs, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 110th Annual Dinner Dance, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 110th Annual Dinner and Dance RSVPs, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 119th Annual Dinner, 2018 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Seneca Club Dinner Committee Stamps, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Series 4: Electoral Campaigns, 1928-2009
  This series contains electoral campaign materials, including ephemera produced by candidates, as well as materials produced by the Sencea Club itself. Candidates that are particularly well-represented in this series include Abe Beame, Al Lownstein, George Swetnick, and Steve Cohn. This series also includes one ledger containing handwritten and published election results, clippings, and campaign advertisements from 1928 through 1966 concerning races for a variety of national, state, and local positions. Other materials included in the ledger are election appeals sent out by the Club with voting guidance, poll information, and candidate photographs with a suggestion to take these recommendations into the voting booth. The series also includes a sample voting machine.
  - 4th Assembly District Map, 1963 (Object Roll 1)
  - 50th Assembly District Alternate Delegates Signatories, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 57th Assembly District Maps, 1972-1974 (Flat file folder 1)
  - Abe Beame Campaign Materials, circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Al Lowenstein Campaign Materials, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - County Committee, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Designating Petition Instructions, circa 1970s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Election District Interpreters, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Election Night Tally Charts, 1969-1978 (Box 10, Folder 8, Flat file folder 1, Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Election Night Tally Sheets, 1961-1968 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Election Results Ledger, 1928-1966 (Box 11)
  - Electoral Campaign Posters, 1960-2009 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - George Swetnick Electoral Campaign, 1962-1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Inspectors of Election, 57th Assembly District, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Kings County Polling Places, circa 1970s (Flat file folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Campaign Materials, 1960s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pollwatcher Information, 1980-1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Primary Day Electoral District Tally Sheets, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Sample Ballots, circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 9, Box 10)
  - Sample Voting Machine, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Seneca Club Campaign Materials, 1958-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Steve Cohn Electoral Campaign, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Series 5: Photographs and Plaques, 1940-1998
  This series includes photographs of Seneca Club events and members, as well as photographs of affiliated organizations and prominent politicians. There are a number of unidentified photographs in this series. This series also contains six plaques presented to Seneca Club members.
  - Basketball, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Building Damage, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Clemente Sukkah, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Dinner-Dance, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Election Campaigns, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Events, 1963, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Harold Cohn United Jewish Appeal Plaque, 1964 (Box 23)
  - Harold Cohn Wallabout Houses Plaque, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Harvey Strelzin Membership Plaque, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Jewish War Veterans of King County, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Operation Understanding Photo Album, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
  - Pen Certificate for Act to Amend Retirement and Social Security, 1966 (Box 24)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Portraits on Printing Plates, undated (Box 20)
  - Presidents, United States, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Seneca Club Little League Baseball, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10, Box 10)
  - Steve Cohn Independence Towers Tenants Association Plaque, 1998 (Box 23)
  - Steve Cohn United Negro College Fund Plaque, 1986 (Box 23)
  - Unidentified Photographs, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 4, Box 10, Box 8, Folder 14, Flat file folder 1)
  - US Army Plaque in Memory of Private Louis Sobel, 1918 (Box 24)
  - War Veterans, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series 6: Membership Cards, circa 1950 to 1980 (Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 21, Box 22)
  Membership cards were maintained at the Seneca Club offices, and were used by the organization's leadership to track members and their interactions with the Seneca Club. Membership cards include names, addresses, and dates and descritpions of individual assistance provided by the Seneca Club. The Seneca Club frequently provided neighborhood residents with assistance in housing, employment, immigration, military status, and more. This information was used to encourage voter turnout during election campaigns.
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. There was no apparent intellectual arrangment of the membership cards at the time of donation.